<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<publication>
	<citation>Nike Stam, 'Glosses on Óengus mac Óengobann, <i>Félire Óenguso</i>, in Oxford, Bodleian Library, Rawlinson B505'</citation>
	<doi>10.71555/stam2024</doi>
	<publish_date>2024-09-05</publish_date>
	<about><p>This transcription was produced under the auspices of the NWO Vrije Competitie Project 
‘<a href="https://medievalirishbilingualism.sites.uu.nl/publications/">Medieval Irish Bilingualism</a>’, which
ran at Utrecht University from 2012–2016.</p>

<p>The transcription of the glosses was made by Nike Stam and formed the
basis of her thesis ‘<a href="https://www.lotpublications.nl/a-typology-of-code-switching-in-the-commentary-to-the-f%C3%A9lire-%C3%B3engusso">A
Typology of Code-Switching in the Commentary to the <i>Félire Óengusso</i></a>’, in which the <b>bilingual glosses</b>
were translated and analysed. The editorial policy and the XML encoding policy are explained on pp 155–162. 
For the bilingual glosses and their translations, see pp 475–545.
All the glosses have been marked up for language; the bilingual glosses also contain PoS tags. This XML-file is Open Access and available upon request.</p>

<p>Mike Olson (Emerging Standards Project) and Martijn van der Klis (Digital
Humanities Utrecht University) created a framework for the XML editor oXygen that was used during the project, which is downloadable via
<a href="https://github.com/odaata/HisTEI/tree/master/frameworks">github</a>.
Similarly, a Python script developed by Martijn van der Klis to extract glosses from the database may be found on <a href="https://github.com/odaata/HisTEI/tree/master/python">github</a>.</p>

<p>This online publication presents all glosses on the months January–December,
including the monolingual Irish and Latin glosses. <b>Note, however, that these monolingual glosses have not been translated or
analysed, and that they are therefore more likely to contain transcription errors.</b> 
As these glosses have not been published elsewhere and as the manuscript 
<a href="https://medieval.bodleian.ox.ac.uk/catalog/manuscript_8070">Rawlinson B505</a> has not been digitized yet, it is hoped that they may provide an
initial steppingstone for those interested in the study of the Commentary to the <i>Félire Óengusso</i>.
</p>

<p>The aim of this publication is to create a ‘live’ edition, which is open to corrections and additions. Nike Stam welcomes any corrections: 
<a href="mailto:n.stam@uu.nl">n.stam@uu.nl</a>. As it stands now, the preface, prologue and epilogue are excluded, as 
are any potential glosses that they contain, and Nike Stam hopes to continue work on this at a later stage. 
</p></about>
</publication>
