<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<publication>
	<citation>Evina Stein, 'Glosses on Isidore, <i>Etymologiae</i>, book 1'</citation>
	<doi>https://doi.org/10.71555/stein2024</doi>
	<publish_date>2024-12-18</publish_date>
	<about>
	
<p>The glosses to the Etymologiae were transcribed as a part of the NWO
VENI project '<a href="https://innovatingknowledge.nl/">Innovating
Knowledge: Isidore's Etymologiae in the Carolingian Period</a>' (VENI
project 275-50-016) carried out at the Huygens Institute in Amsterdam
in 2018-2021. </p>

<p>The glosses to the first book of the
Etymologiae are also published separately as E. Steinova and P. Boot,
<i>The glosses to the first book of the Etymologiae of Isidore of
Seville: a digital scholarly edition</i>, Huygens Institute: Amsterdam,
2021, at: <a href="https://db.innovatingknowledge.nl/edition">https://db.innovatingknowledge.nl/edition</a>.
The editorial standardisation and treatment are discussed in the
introductory sections of the digital edition.</p>

<p>The XML encoding of these glosses is described in E. Steinova and P. Boot,
'<a href="https://osf.io/preprints/osf/7auxz">Editing Glosses as
Networks: Exploring the Explorative Edition</a>', in: <i>A Companion to
Digital Editing Methods</i>, ed. E. Bleeker et al., forthcoming.</p>

<p>The collection of glosses and layers of glossing in individual
manuscripts, including the glossing hands, are analysed in E.
Steinova, 'Annotation of the Etymologiae of Isidore of Seville in Its
Early Medieval Context', <i>ALMA</i> 78 (2020), 5–81.</p>

<p>The network-based analysis and visualisation of the glosses to the first
book of the Etymologiae are discussed in E. Stein, '<a href="https://jhnr.net/articles/10.25517/jhnr.v9i1.198">Parallel
Glosses, Shared Glosses, and Gloss Clustering: Can Network-Based
Approach Help Us to Understand Organic Corpora of Glosses?</a>', <i>JHNR</i>
9 (2023), 36–100.</p>

<p>An Excel datasheet with the glosses to
the first book of the Etymologiae is published on Zenodo at:
<a href="https://zenodo.org/records/5767868">https://zenodo.org/records/5767868</a>.</p>

	
	</about>
</publication>
